(BLUES MUSIC PLAYING)
RONNY: You've got
to picture this.
It was freshman year,
there he is,
completely naked,
right outside the office!
RONNY: And he says,
"Ronny told me to show up."
GENEVA: Hey,
I have a question
for the table.
How long does it take
to really know someone?
BETH:
I think you're continually
getting to know someone.
'Cause I think
people change
when they grow.
But I do think
if you go through
hell with someone,
then you get
a pretty good sense of
how they handle stuff,
which is important.
Come on, we're on
the other side of
that one.
I don't know.
I think you can
know someone within the first
10 seconds of seeing them.
I mean,
I fell in love with Geneva
the second I saw her.
Aw...
It's true. I did.
RONNY: Well, I don't know
if you ever really know
someone entirely.
And what is that
supposed to mean?
Yeah.
Well, I mean,
you know someone,
you think pretty good,
and then you find out
stuff that's shocking that
you didn't know existed.
I think that happens
every day.
Look at that show 20/20,
it's always the same thing,
right?
They're a couple,
they're happy,
no one could believe it.
There are a lot
of these cases.
What about the guy
with the crossbow?
He buys a crossbow,
he's practicing
in the garage.
"By the way,
bring me some lemonade.
"Oh, my goodness,
I had no idea you walked
through at that moment. Oops!"
Continue, please.
Continue.
BETH: That is gross!
But she forgives him.
It was an accident,
and guess what?
Six months later,
same accident.
Yes, and it kills her.
No!
Yes!
(LAUGHS) No!
And, lookit,
you hear all the time
about these families
that have entirely
other families.
The dad, who knows what
he does for a living,
he leaves to go
to Connecticut.
But he was never
going to Connecticut
on business.
He's really going to Harlem.
He's got a Puerto Rican family
that no one ever
heard about.
Yeah.
You think when he's watching
the game, instead of pretzels,
he's eating Goya beans.
Red flags,
but they don't catch it.
So my point is,
you can really think
you know somebody,
and then it turns out that
you don't know everything
about somebody.
All right, Ronny.
You still haven't
answered the question.
No, I just did.
You didn't.
No, you didn't answer it.
You're skirting it.
You're not answering
straight up.
Come on.
You're bouncing around,
you're doing this, "Hey!"
When you're doing this...
You do that a lot,
by the way.
I think you're all
special peoples.
You're out of your mind!
And you're nothing
of the sort.
(CHATTERING)
(CAMERA CLICKS)
(MAN ANNOUNCING ON PA)
This is our shot.
I need you to hug him.
I don't want to hug him.
Lookit, ever since he had
a near-death experience,
he's become
a very touchy-feely guy,
and he likes to be held.
Look, you know
I don't like touching people
I don't know very well, okay?
Or even people I do.
So just...
Nick, do you want
this thing or not?
Of course I do.
Then feed the beast here!
This guy has a hot button,
a point of interest.
His hot button is hugs.
You hug him,
you're gonna crack
him wide open!
He's going to start
feeling all bubbly inside.
Then he starts
writing checks!
All right.
I'm not asking you to
go to an airport motel
and perform a trick
on a Japanese businessman.
I'm asking you to hug
a senior executive from
General Motors, that's all!
Now get your
arms around him,
and make him feel
bubbly and warm!
I'll tell you what.
Why don't you let Charles
take you guys over here
and show you the entire line.
And it's great to
have you here.
Thank you so much
for coming.
MAN: Thank you.
Man!
This puppy here reminds me
of my first Dodge.
Uh-huh?
Remember that?
Remember when cars
were meant just to be
fun things to have, right?
(LAUGHS)
They made a cool noise,
they harnessed real power
and they made you
feel like a badass
because you got to be
the one right there behind
the wheel of it, right?
I'm sorry,
I'm Ronny Valentine from
B & V Engine Design.
Thomas Fern.
Yeah, Thomas,
good to see you again.
We actually helped you out
with a few ECU modules
a few years back.
Of course.
Yeah.
Hey, that's...
There, my partner,
Nick Brannen.
Congrats.
It's gonna be
a great year.
It really is.
Of course.
(WHISPERING) Your soul
was too important to take.
You've got great days
ahead of you, my friend.
You know, we actually have
one idea we're not committed
to anyone on.
We could run it
by your team,
and see if it's something
that made sense for you.
I'd love that.
Maybe we could get
something on the books.
We'll come up there
to Rock City, to Detroit,
and come see you.
Okay.
Yeah.
You lying bastard!
You are unbelievable.
Did we get
the meeting or not?
I'm hugging this man
like I'm some kind
of asshole...
BETH: Now, why were
you hugging the man?
Because he's our guy's
direct competitor.
Why would you hug
the direct competitor?
Because he had
a near-death experience.
RONNY: Actually,
no, he didn't.
That never happened.
I made that up.
(CHUCKLES)
Shame, shame, shame.
What are you doing?
What do you mean,
what am I doing?
Did we get the meeting
or what?
Come on, Nick.
I'm never hugging again.
I'm not listening to you.
He sets me up!
What do you expect me to do?
Geneva, listen to me.
You know him,
he's way too honest.
If I fill him in on it,
what happens?
The sweating,
he starts hyperventilating,
he passes out!
It was completely necessary.
Nick, my man,
we got the meeting.
I'm not gonna lie.
Sometimes,
I love your boyfriend.
You, I will hug.
This is free.
I'll hug you right back!
This is no charge!
Come in here!
My man!
Don't ever let me go.
(BLUES MUSIC PLAYING)
They've had
a couple of lessons.
Yeah!
Okay, let's dance.
Less is more.
I'm dancing on the inside.
Are you dancing
right now?
Yes.
Oh, okay.
Honey, listen,
you can never trust
a man who dances.
Look at the great men
throughout history,
none of them were dancers.
Abraham Lincoln?
Not a big dancer.
Winston Churchill,
he never tore up
the dance floor.
Martin Luther King,
he might've had a dream,
but he never danced to it.
Okay, come on.
I'm serious.
Come on,
tiny dancer,
let's go.
You plant it
here right now.
Look, you think
they're great,
and they're dancing.
RONNY: I think
they're better than great.
I think they're the best.
When it comes
to being a couple,
they're my heroes.
Hey!
Come on, why you sitting?
Get up, let's do this!
Oh, Nick, you know,
Ronny here,
he just called you
his hero couple,
and yet he still refuses
to dance with me.
Will you stop?
Do not give him ammo.
(STUTTERS)
Ronny just told Beth
I'm his hero.
I'm your hero!
You're the worst.
Oh, come on.
Every kid wants to
dance with his hero!
Bring it up here!
Let's do it.
Yo!
Blue! Set! Hut! Hut!
Go long, baby! Go long!
Yes!
Whoo-hoo!
My man.
That just happened.
Oh, yeah.
I don't think
I'll ever forget that!
Oh, great. Is that burned
in the hard drive now?
Mmm-hmm. I think so.
Excuse me.
Hey, I need to do this.
Let me show you
how this is done.
Be my guest.
Come on, pal.
I think
you're stuck with me.
So when are you
gonna ask her?
What?
Come on, Ronny!
You can see it
all over her face!
You're never gonna
find a girl
as great as her.
Let's be realistic.
Nick and I aren't making
any new friends.
You've dated
all my girlfriends.
You've batted through
the whole lineup,
and there's nothing left,
you know?
Plus, we like her.
Those other ones,
we didn't even like,
and they're my friends!
Trust me.
Pop the question or
you're gonna lose her.
NICK: (LAUGHS)
There you go!
Hey, hey!
Special delivery!
How's that for an entrance?
You were missed.
I missed you, too.
(CHUCKLES)
What?
Nothing.
Now I'm gonna
turn up the heat.
What happens when the kitchen
gets hot, because I'm cooking
something up, chef.
Don't play into my strength.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
Whoo!
Fifteen to four!
(LAUGHS)
Really?
You're gonna start...
Now you're dancing?
It's like I'm playing
Floyd Mayweather at Ping-Pong.
That's ridiculous.
You're only supposed
to do that
if the game's over.
If the game's over.
I'm just being happy,
you know?
No, no,
you're not being happy.
This is a taunting.
This is, like,
taunting that's going on.
I'm sorry.
You're not sorry,
that's the problem.
I know. You're right.
Okay, here's what
we need to do now.
'Cause I think
you're very spirited,
and I like that.
I think we should turn it into
full-body-contact Ping-Pong.
(LAUGHS EXCITEDLY)
Yes, we do!
Come on, you can't taunt
people bigger than you
and expect it
just to be all fine.
Help! (SCREAMS)
(LAUGHING)
You're attacked.
Yes! That's it.
Are you gonna try
and steal a kiss now?
Go on, I dare you.
I want to let you know,
by the way,
that I'm completely committed
to this relationship.
I'm just re-upping.
I'm already committed,
but I'm just re-upping
my commitment
to this relationship
because I feel great.
How do you feel?
Do you feel great?
Uh-huh.
Yeah?
Mmm-hmm. I feel great.
(SLOW LOVE SONG PLAYING)
But is there a window?
Are you anxious for this
to go somewhere?
Ronny, Ronny, I know you.
I know where
you're headed with this.
Look,
I don't need this to be
something that it's not.
I don't want it to
be something if it's not,
just to make me okay.
But is there a clock
that's ticking?
Are you in a hurry
to be heading somewhere?
There's always a clock.
And I'm worrying,
is it ticking,
getting to a point
where the clock's
gonna go off?
Let's just talk
through this, okay?
Yeah.
I have fun with you.
I love being with you.
I think we've done
a great job of getting back
to a really good place.
I'm happy.
Now, if all of that rolls
into something else,
that can make me happy, too.
I love you.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
Okay, Ronny.
You can do this.
This is your time to do it.
You the man, Valentine.
You're the man.
MALE STEWARD ON PA: Folks,
this is our final approach
to Detroit's Metro Airport.
(EXHALES NERVOUSLY)
Hope this goes well.
Great moments are born
from great opportunity.
And that's what you have
here today, Nick.
That's what
you've earned
here today!
One meeting.
(STAMMERS) Okay,
what are you doing?
You're giving me
the... Really?
The Kurt Russell speech
from the movie Miracle?
I just saw
that five-year-old kid do it
on YouTube the other night,
and I thought it was
really inspirational.
It's applicable
to what we're doing.
Any time you go into
a pressure situation,
a competition, it makes sense.
And I'm not gonna
write something
better than that.
Look at you,
you're nervous.
You're never nervous.
Now, you're nervous.
Okay, here's the thing.
I can't be broke
if I'm gonna get married.
Yeah?
Yes! See, I knew
you would get here!
Okay, so here's my plan.
I'm gonna
ask her next month,
on her birthday.
Now, I worked out
this great deal
from this Hasidic guy,
who I met during
Gamblers Anonymous.
He's literally gonna give me
a $20,000 ring for $10,000.
Can you believe that?
How are you doing that?
Well, I'm gonna
give him cash.
And then I also said
that you would help
fix his car.
So those two little things
are gonna get me
the deal with the Hasidic.
Oh, I'm helping?
I'm helping fix the car?
Well, you're the one
who kept telling me
to dive into it.
I thought you'd be
excited to help.
I'm sorry.
Okay, fine, but
that is my gift to you.
Honestly,
there'll be no fruit bowl
from the registry.
That's it. That's what
you're looking at.
You don't have to make
a decision now.
On the day,
see what's right...
No, I'm making... I can make
the decision now.
I'm making it now.
I'm telling you right now,
that is my gift.
That's it.
I'm fixing the car
with the Hasidic guy.
And make sure
you tell Beth that, too.
Seriously, I don't want it
to be uncomfortable.
Let her know.
Whatever you wanna do
on that day is your choice.
Okay. I'm doing it.
You take
this meeting 10 times,
you might not get it nine.
All right, you got
to stop that now.
But not this meeting, Nick.
Not today.
(EXHALES) You're really
making me nervous.
Today,
we are the greatest small
business in the world.
I'm sick and tired of
hearing about how innovative
these other boutiques are.
This is our time.
Their time is done!
We're showing up in a cab.
NICK: Thanks for not
mentioning that my last three
prototype bids got rejected.
That's just
a bad streak, pal.
You're gonna be great,
I promise you.
(EXHALES)
Here you go.
Ladies and gentlemen,
electric cars,
they're totally gay.
It's true.
I don't mean that
they're "homosexual" gay,
but I do mean "your parents
were the chaperone
at the dance" gay. Right?
"You tuck it in
and wear it real high" gay.
I don't wanna
disrespect anybody,
'cause I'm not about that.
But I think
we're understanding
what we're trying to
talk about here, right?
I mean, honestly,
the Nissan Spit? Really?
It screams this.
Oh, here we go.
The Hyundai Pomegranate.
Right?
The Chevy Fingerprint.
Now,
ah, look at this.
The 1966 Ford GT350.
You wanna roll up
in that one, hoss?
The 1965 Pontiac GTO.
Completely awesome.
The 1970 Hemi Cuda
took more virginities
than Francis Albert Sinatra.
What are we suggesting here?
We're talking about
taking the benefits
of electric transportation,
but combine them
with the rock and roll-ness
and the sexiness
that the Dodge current
muscle-car models have.
Nicholas?
We believe we could
produce the technology
to incorporate
an electronic motor in
your current models.
But with the aggressive
sound character,
the exhilarating
vibration character,
the complete
visceral experience
that we've all grown
to know and love in the Dodge
Challenger and Charger lines.
SUSAN: Guys, we love our
current electric models.
That said, we also
agree there's a market
for what you're pitching.
But, if you're asking
Dodge to invest in
your pursuit of this concept,
what do you have
that we don't?
Nick Brannen.
(BREATHES NERVOUSLY)
So let's forget
the up-front money.
Let's deal with it in success
because that's exactly
what we're gonna have.
I want 900,000,
you want 400,000.
We don't need to get
a Chinese auction where I go,
"850." You go, "450," right?
"Eight." "Five."
Let's just cut it right
down the middle at 775,
and close this thing.
(LAUGHS)
I appreciate your spirit,
Mr. Valentine.
But we're taking
all the risk,
so we'll stick
with the 400,000.
And I think you need to focus
on the bigger picture, here.
With success
and a good working
relationship,
we're prepared to offer you
an overall deal, which means
up-front money
and an option
for an exclusive long-term
contract with your company.
And with that deal,
you gentlemen won't
be disappointed.
You made a great
decision today, Tom.
Thank you.
You'll be under
the supervision of
Susan Warner, here.
She's from the outside,
but we've had great
experience with her.
SUSAN: You know, I was at Ford
until about five months ago.
They're still talking
about you guys over there.
They said you could
whittle down a supplier
to less than 15 cents
on the dollar
just by talking.
And you were like
a mad scientist that wouldn't
leave the lab for days.
Well, boys,
it takes one to know one.
I'm one of you.
I'm a visionary,
I'm a maverick,
I'm a gun-slinger,
just like you.
And this idea of yours,
this vision...
(CHUCKLES)
I'm inspired by
what y'all throwing down.
I got some serious
lady wood here.
I want to have sex
with your words.
I want to bang your brain!
(LAUGHS)
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Oh. I got to go.
I'm late for Mommy and Me.
I'll call you.
Bye.
Okay.
At least she's enthusiastic.
(STAMMERING) Ronny,
I got to tell you,
(CLEARS THROAT)
I think I'm starting
to have a panic attack.
What if I can't deliver?
I mean, we sank every cent
we have into this.
We're mortgaged to the hilt,
we're borrowing
against borrowing.
Okay, listen, just relax.
I think you're taking this
all in a little too fast,
just a little too soon.
Now, you said it yourself.
We're on the five-yard line,
we just got to punch it in.
Twenty-five.
What?
I said we were on
the 25-yard line.
Nick, are you suggesting
that we're not even
in the red zone?
Oh, man,
what if I can't do it?
Everybody... Just think,
Dodge is gonna know,
they're gonna laugh at us.
That guy,
that security guard,
he's just laughing.
Look at him,
he's just staring...
Hold on.
Look at the security guard,
he's looking at me.
Okay, stop.
Get it together.
Stop looking at me.
Just take a breath
for a second.
Don't lose perspective here.
You're only five yards
from the red zone.
Now once
we get in the red zone,
we're a mortal lock.
You're a red-zone guy!
Still 25 yards out,
do you understand that?
By the way,
I don't care how you spin it,
how you want to ice the cake,
we're only 75%
of the way there,
and I'm having trouble
breathing now.
(WHISPERING)
You need to relax!
Everything is going
to be fine.
(WHISPERING) I never said
we were in the red zone.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
(PLATES CLATTERING)
So, it's been 10 days
since the meeting,
and he still hasn't
calmed down.
I'm doing my best to keep
his head in the game,
but he's still
a little shaky.
All right, we are going
with the opakapaka tonight.
Okay, but we need
to educate the servers,
please.
They know, chef.
They know.
No, they don't know!
They're fish-illiterate.
What about you, Ronny?
Also fish-illiterate.
I don't know fish.
I'm saying,
how are you doing?
How are you coping
with all of this?
I'm great, honey.
It's been 16 months
and nine days since I made
a bet, I'm easy-breezy.
I'm not talking
about gambling.
I'm just saying,
if you're feeling stressed,
or if things start
to feel heavy...
Yes, heavy.
...then you can
come talk to me.
Honey, if I'm lucky enough
to get you alone
for five minutes,
the last thing
I'm going to do is talk.
Is that so?
Mmm.
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
When did you say
her birthday was?
Two weeks.
Oh, good, we'll have
the new Pacific Calendulas in.
Oh, great.
She'll love that.
Yes, we had a hybridizing
program this winter.
This is awesome!
Wow. This is what
I'm talking about.
See this, right here,
this place here is beautiful.
And the music
that you're playing,
that's really beautiful, too.
People say that music
is the highest art form.
It can go the farthest,
the fastest, emotionally.
And the smells here
are really nice as well.
I love all the smells.
What I'm trying to do is get
all five senses really coming
alive here, really cooking.
Mmm-hmm.
Do you have a plug
in the garden somewhere?
Somewhere I can plug
my iPod dock into.
Anywhere in here?
Back here?
Oh, see, wait, wait, no.
We don't like the guest
touching the plants.
Why? I mean,
if you talk to them,
they grow.
They like a little affection.
I wouldn't pull it out.
I just wanna make sure
that you're taking care of
all the things on your end.
Because I'm going today.
I'm going to have the ring.
So that'll be taken care of.
I trust you'll have a ring.
And I just want to
make sure that this is
the greatest proposal
in the history of
the world of all proposals.
All right? That's it.
Let me see
if I can track down
where that outlet is.
Okay. Get me in
here for a team.
Let's go, "Proposal,"
on three.
Let's have fun with it.
Ready?
Okay.
One, two, three...
Proposal!
My man! Get out
of here, baby!
Make it good.
I'm counting on you.
(WHISPERING)
Beth, come here.
Beth...
GENEVA: Come on.
(IMITATES ELECTRIC
GUITAR PLAYING)
(LAUGHING)
Can we go already?
I'm tired of
looking at plants.
Damn it!
Mr. Valentine?
(PANTS)
Son of a bitch.
Don't do it,
Geneva. Jesus.
Oh, God.
What are you doing?
(GRUNTING)
Ah!
Those plants
are poisonous!
Awesome.
You can expect diarrhea,
challenging urination
with possible
bloody discharge,
fever, dry-heaving,
painful swelling of the gums
and a loss of feeling
in the tongue,
which will affect speech
and give you very bad dreams.
You are banned from
these gardens indefinitely.
(ECHOING) So you can
forget about popping
the question here!
"Proposal on three."
We are not teammates.
As far as damages,
it's going to run
into the thousands.
I just saw
my best friend's wife
with another man.
I'll send you a check.
It's very red.
Looks really angry.
(SHARP EXHALE)
I didn't think you were
allergic to anything.
Neither did I.
Huh. What kind
of plants were they?
Street plants.
Street plants?
Yeah. It must've happened
when I was walking on Clark,
because I had to go...
These kids lost their ball,
and I had to go
in the bushes
and get their ball.
Why couldn't they get
their own ball?
Well, you know
how these kids are today,
they're so damn lazy.
I mean, with all the gaming,
and texting, and Happy Meals.
I mean, childhood obesity
is completely out of control.
You know that, Beth.
And these kids were just
overly huffing and puffing,
and they were sweating.
All right. Well, I don't see
why that means they can't go
get their own ball.
Well, to their credit,
these little porkers
were trying,
but they couldn't
reach the ball.
This little
alligator-armed kid
was in there doing it,
but the little kid,
he can't get the ball.
So then I come walking up,
and they say,
"Hey, can you help me
with the ball here?"
So I say, "Okay,
I'm running late,"
but these kids want to
play ball, and frankly,
I'm a supporter of it.
Now that we're all gonna be
on the same damn healthcare,
too.
I'm paying for
these fat kids.
Boom! I drop
to the ground.
So now, I'm reaching
in here like this
trying to get
the ball, see?
But I don't want this
branch to hit me here.
Right.
I'm doing it. You see
what I mean, honey?
And I got to dig in more,
under the branch,
but hold the branch.
But then my right hand's
going here.
See, that's why I got
this bitch right here.
Oh.
That's a direct contact.
And I get the ball.
Now I get it.
I got the ball out,
"Okay, here."
Gave the ball
back to the kids,
then I started to
head home. Right?
And then that's when I noticed
that my arm was really itching
and I thought that
it was because I rubbed
up against the brush.
(CHUCKLING EXHALE)
Why are you carrying
so much cash, Ronny?
Well, I was on my way
to the suppliers,
before I helped
the fat kids
with the ball.
(STAMMERS) But, boy,
thank goodness it fell
out here. That's great.
Because, could you imagine
if it would've fallen out
there? Wow.
Yeah, that's a lot of cash.
Well, you know
my suppliers
deal in cash.
But do you mind
if I don't dial into
all the details right now?
I'm just starting
to really itch,
so I'd rather just go
and take care of this
real quick.
How was your day?
It was okay.
(PANTS UNZIPPING)
(DEEP BREATH)
(URINATING)
(GROANS) God! Damn it!
Are you all right?
No, honey, to be honest,
I'm feeling
a little challenged here.
Oh!
(GRUNTING) Oh, God!
(URINATING)
Ow!
God!
(SCREAMING IN PAIN)
NICK: Heat it up.
Is the sub-amp active?
Bring it up.
(ENGINE REVVING)
NICK: Yeah!
All right, you guys
will process the data?
MAN: You got it.
All right,
let's do this!
Nick, I need to talk
to you for a second.
Hey.
Did you go to Burnham Bank
and sign the loan forms yet?
Not yet,
but I wanted to...
You need to go.
I signed them two days ago.
You need to sign them.
And that woman,
Susan from Chrysler,
she keeps calling.
She keeps
calling me "bro."
How am I going to
concentrate with her
calling all the time?
I thought you were going to
run interference on that.
I will.
Ulcer acting up again?
No, no, no, you know what?
This prescribed medical shit
right here,
chalky shit, it's actually
very thirst-quenching.
I can't get enough of it,
I really can't. Thank you.
Just give me
a second here, would you?
All right, boys, let's do it.
Come on, let's awaken
the beast here. Come on!
We've got a solid
reference measurement
this time. Looks good.
The last one
was pathetic,
you know?
If I can talk to you
for one second...
Hey, am I working here?
Am I not working here?
Do I look like I'm working?
David, jump in there.
Fire it up, come on!
All right.
(ENGINE STARTING)
All right, bring it.
Bring it up.
(ENGINE REVVING)
Come on!
FELIX: Stay on it.
There you go.
Finally! Okay, finally,
I'm seeing fractional
orders here.
This might be it.
(ENGINE ROARING)
FELIX: All right!
Fourth order,
pulling ahead...
Come on, pump
that sub right.
Yes!
It's happening!
Yes! Yes! Yes!
Whoo-hoo!
FELIX: Hold on,
hold on, hold on.
The fractional orders
are deviating.
No, no. No, they're not.
Come on, now.
(ENGINE CRACKLING)
MAN: What have we got?
What have we got?
Where we at?
No, no!
Damn it!
We lost the fourth
completely.
Maybe a heavier amp,
bigger subs.
The second and third
were solid until...
Hey, I get it.
I suck, okay?
I suck.
(PANTS)
Nick...
What is it, Ron?
What do you want?
I want to talk to you
about something
that's kind of personal.
Something that doesn't
have to do with any of this.
Do you mind
just stepping up with me
in the office real quick?
You want to go to the office,
talk about something personal
that doesn't have
to do with this?
(WHISPERS) Yeah.
You know,
I'm bleeding inside.
There's blood where
it shouldn't be in my body,
out of (STAMMERS) things.
I've thrown up four times
in the last two days,
which doesn't make any sense,
because I haven't eaten
in three.
So I don't even know
where it's coming from!
Hey, listen,
I understand what
you're saying...
You're not in the pressure
cooker, man! You're not!
When I said I was on
the 25-yard line, I'm not.
I'm much further
back than that.
We are deep
in our own end zone.
Right back there, yeah.
And I'm flushed
out of the pocket,
and the defense
is coming for me,
and they're big, man!
They're fast!
Ah! They're coming!
And I turn to you,
my lead blocker.
You turn to me, "Hey.
"You want to go upstairs
and talk in the office
about something personal?"
Just block!
That's what I need you
to do, is just block!
And do me a favor,
would you sign
the damn loan forms?
So I have somebody
to fund my failure?
Unless you just want
to kiss that long-term
contract goodbye.
(SIGHING)
Unbelievable, huh?
The Bulls? I know,
it's ridiculous.
I mean, Rose should've
passed to Noah.
He was wide open,
completely unguarded.
I know, man, they just can't
get it together at all.
Yeah. I mean, if you ask me,
Rose doesn't trust Noah.
They're teammates.
He doesn't trust he can
hit the winning shot.
Sucks, man.
Yeah, because trust
really runs deep on a team.
You got to be able
to trust your teammate.
Do you think that you have to
be able to trust your teammate
off the court as well?
Uh... Sure.
Let's just say,
and I'm talking completely
hypothetically here,
let's say that Noah finds out
that Derek Rose's girl
is cheating.
Does he tell him or not?
Because he doesn't want
to affect his performance.
Yeah. I mean, he's...
No, no.
Yeah, you tell him.
No.
It's toxic
to keep all that in.
You have to tell him.
That's Guy Code.
You're talking about
your best friend.
You ever hear the expression,
"Kill the messenger"?
'Cause, I mean...
Yeah, but I don't think
it applies here at all.
I mean,
if you don't tell your friend,
your best friend,
then you're basically
banging her, too.
Okay, come on, now.
It depends.
Is it the playoffs?
Game seven,
the championship.
Championship.
No, then
I wouldn't tell him.
Yeah, no way.
No.
Don't tell him.
Nope. You wait.
You wait.
RONNY: Hey, sis.
Just checking in.
DIANE: Ronny, you never
call to just "check in."
You know what happened?
I saw this episode of
Springer,
and I just can't shake
what happened on the episode.
This woman found out that
her best friend's husband
was cheating on her,
and she did not
tell her friend.
Ronny, why are you
telling me this?
Bowling.
I just want to
get your take on it.
What do you think?
Do you think she should
have told her best friend
that her husband
was cheating?
Of course she should.
But what about the whole
"kill the messenger" thing?
You know what I mean?
Ronny, she is doing
her friend a favor.
It doesn't matter
how painful the moment...
Mom, come on!
Okay, Ronny,
I got to go, I'm sorry.
Okay. Bye-bye.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Hello?
Nice disguise, Ronny.
Making it a woman
on Jerry Springer?
Bullshit!
I am not an idiot.
What?
You want to tell me
Saul's cheating on me?
Just say it!
Diane, listen.
I don't think you understand
what I'm saying.
I'm not saying
anything about Saul.
I'm gonna kill him!
You don't need
to kill anybody.
I really thought
I was done with choosing men
who were basically Dad.
I mean, who would even sleep
with that out-of-work slob?
Okay, Diane, listen to me,
you're way overreacting.
How dare you tell me
something like this
over the phone?
How dare you tell me
this at all?
And screw you, Ronny!
You have always been
a selfish little asshole.
What? Why am I an asshole?
(STUTTERING)
F-you, Ronny!
Ah, geez.
NICK: All right, now,
that's a little better.
Where's the cross-over?
(CAR ENGINE REVVING)
Yeah, this is nice.
This is nice.
WOMAN: Hey, Ronny.
What's up?
Ronny.
Can I talk to you
for a second?
I was actually gonna
run up here for about
the rest of the day.
Just one second, please.
It's important.
(CLEARS THROAT)
One second.
Come on.
Look.
I am so sorry.
I've been thinking too much
about myself lately,
and I'm throwing tantrums
because a car is not
loud enough.
So I have eight minutes.
Eight minutes?
Yeah.
Yeah, I have a call at 5:00,
with Helmut Farber in Berlin.
He's going to give me
some pointers
on throttle response.
So I have eight
uninterrupted minutes
to talk about whatever it is
you wanted to talk about.
Right.
Ronny, you have
seven minutes and
48 seconds to just chat.
(WHISPERS) Open up.
(CLEARS THROAT)
What I wanted to
talk to you about...
Yes, Ronny?
...was proposing to Beth.
(STAMMERS)
You didn't propose yet?
Why not?
Well, I wasn't sure that
I found the right exact
place to do that.
Oh, come on.
Ronny, come on, man.
You're just sabotaging
yourself, that's what
you're doing here.
Don't you understand,
once you get into it,
it's gonna be fine?
I'm telling you,
you found the right...
What the hell is
that on your arm?
What is going on?
I had an outbreak.
(STAMMERING)
I broke out in
hives everywhere.
(WHISPERS) And when I piss,
it kind of burns, too.
MAN: Ronny, Nick,
your better halves are here.
Wow, now that is
a sexy car.
Whoo! If only
it were fuel-efficient.
Hey, sweetheart.
NICK: Hey, honey,
what are you doing here?
GENEVA: Hey, sweetie.
Nice surprise.
I have a special night
planned for you guys.
Hi, Nick.
Hi, sweetie.
Yeah,
but I don't have time
for a night, honey.
We're way behind.
Well, you're behind
because you guys are
burning yourselves out.
You got to
recharge the engine,
get some perspective.
I don't think
we have the time
for perspective.
I don't know that
tonight's a good night
for us to go do anything.
I know you don't
want to celebrate,
because you guys
haven't gotten a line yet.
So it's not
a celebration.
We're just thinking
maybe we could take
a breather
to set the table
for a possible
potential celebration
sometime in the future.
Yeah.
And, listen, I called here
to talk to you earlier,
and I talked to Felix,
and he said
things were getting
pretty heated today.
I think you guys need
a break, you know?
This is not a discussion.
We are doing this.
And you, my friend,
are going to thank me
for this later.
What happened
to your face?
ANNOUNCER ON PA:
That was his second attempt.
Now, here is his third
and final attempt
to win the round-trip
airline tickets
anywhere in
the United States.
You don't give
yourself a nickname.
(PEOPLE CHEERING)
(BOOING)
ANNOUNCER ON PA: Good try
by our second contestant.
Come on.
I've been trying to take
that shot for 10 years,
they don't pick me.
They never pick me.
I don't know
what I got to do.
Our third
and final contestant,
Jessica Hill from
Park Ridge, Illinois.
Tell you one thing,
if they did pick me,
I'm sticking it in the net.
That's a no-brainer,
right there.
You know
I was third in scoring
at Ball State? Third.
They didn't cut anybody.
It was a club team.
ANNOUNCER ON PA:
Good first attempt
for Jessica.
Why you got to take away
my accomplishments?
I'm not.
No, you are, okay?
I'm a shooter, it's what I am.
Just deal with it, all right?
"Sniper."
They called me
"The Sniper."
I'm just saying,
it's not that easy to
put in from center ice
into that big of a hole.
It's not easy.
That's why
a few of us can do it.
I'm saying I can do it.
You know what...
Have you ever done it?
No. It doesn't matter.
It doesn't matter, though.
I'd put it in,
believe me.
ANNOUNCER ON PA:
That was a wide
to the right...
It's not a net.
It's a hole that's this big.
It doesn't...
Yeah, it's a big...
They know
what they're doing.
They do statistics to
make sure that a certain
amount of people miss it.
NICK: I mean, I don't know
how much you've dealt
with athletes.
I can see things
differently.
Everything just
comes to a blur.
It's like you're locked
in maple syrup,
and you're moving slow
and you see things happening
before they do happen.
(GRUNTING)
You guys,
I'm gonna go get some beer.
Do you want anything?
No, no, babe.
I'm good, thanks.
ANNOUNCER ON PA:
Blackhawks penalty
caller number 81...
(LAUGHS EXCITEDLY)
I'm gonna go
help her with the beers.
I'm gonna get one.
You guys want anything?
I'm good, thanks.
Pretzels, all right?
All right.
Yeah, pretzels.
(CROWD EXCLAIMS)
Boy, you've been
on that all night.
(TIMIDLY) Hey.
I saw you yesterday.
You saw me where?
At the Botanical Gardens.
So?
I saw it all, Geneva.
The loser with
the Dead Milkmen T-shirt.
Kissing him
in broad daylight.
Okay, Ronny, I got it.
You got a great guy
who's considerate
to people,
and who cares about you,
and you're out running on him.
Don't put this all on me.
How dare you ambush me
with what you think you know?
What I think I know?
I saw you mauling the guy,
Geneva.
Ronny, you don't know shit.
You don't know shit.
You do not know
what goes on behind the
curtains of a marriage.
Like the fact that
he hasn't slept with me
for over six months.
Don't stand there
and start talking
nonsense to me.
No, you know what?
Are you serious?
How about the fact
that every Thursday night
after work,
Nick goes to Pilsen,
to a massage parlor,
where he gets wanked
by a 19-year-old
Vietnamese girl
who speaks
four words of English!
How about that?
I don't believe a word
you're saying right now.
(SCOFFS)
Yeah, you're just
covering your ass.
(CROWD CHEERING)
Listen to me.
Nick is my very best friend
in the entire world.
I know.
And I am never, ever,
ever going to keep
this from him.
Do you understand?
So I'm coming to you now,
and I'm giving you
an opportunity,
but you need to
deal with this.
But it only happened
because my husband
wasn't intimate with me!
I'm not a marriage
counselor.
I don't want to be
a marriage counselor!
Let's make it really,
really simple then.
Either you tell him,
or I will.
I can't.
I will.
No, no. Ronny, no!
Yes.
No, Ronny. No.
Don't do this now.
Not while this
Chrysler thing
is going on.
Listen, Nick is not
sleeping at night.
His stomach is
literally bleeding.
This would destroy him.
You're not going to see
this guy anymore?
No! God, no!
That was stupid.
I know that was stupid.
And it's over.
It's over because
it never was.
Then why have you been
texting him all night?
Have I?
Yeah, you have.
Sitting on
the BlackBerry,
banging people.
Your sister just
bought a new dress.
Just like I was saying, Ronny,
you don't know shit.
Are you promising me
that as soon as
this bit is over...
Yes!
...you're gonna tell him,
and you're gonna tell him
about this guy
that you kissed?
Are you promising me that?
I absolutely
swear to God, yes.
(BLUES ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
(MEN CHATTERING)
(STAMMERS)
I'm so disappointed
in you, Ronny.
Okay.
(DEEP EXHALE)
Just pick a date
and ask Beth to marry you.
You're making this thing
out to be much more
than it needs to be.
And now your stress
is causing me stress.
That's right,
I'm stressing out
like crazy. Yeah.
You're right.
You're totally right.
Now that you verbalize it,
and I hear it,
you're completely right, man.
Thank you.
Now I'm a guy causing
extra damn stress.
(SIGHS)
You ever get a massage?
Hmm?
In times like this,
when it gets very stressful,
do you get a massage?
Have I had a massage?
I mean, no, not really.
Really, no.
You can only do
so much yourself.
You can do things yourself,
but when you get
a professional to get that,
take it out of you
and get that stress
right out of you,
throw it out of you.
Hey, Nick,
you know what could
be tremendous?
Maybe me and you could go
and get a massage together.
I don't mean
in the same room or something.
I mean at the same place.
Do you know a place
we could do that?
Where we could
get a massage?
A place that could take us
to relax, relax, relax.
Here's what I'm trying
to say to you, okay?
Don't let fear sabotage
letting yourself be happy.
You guys are great together.
You're in love.
And love can be very rewarding
and it can be very filling.
Very filling.
Like a warm stew.
It honestly is.
Look, if you want
ice cream,
go in the car
and get ice cream.
You don't worry that,
"While I'm driving,
"hey, I might have
some chest pains,"
and then,
"Turns out, heart attack.
I'm having a heart attack!"
You veer off,
you kill a bunch of
seniors and toddlers.
You get your ice cream.
And you know what?
99% of the time, you're gonna
end up at the ice cream shop
with a big hot fudge
sundae. Nuts!
Only one percent of the time
do you kill the innocent.
It's pretty good odds.
I'm not understanding
what you're trying
to say to me.
All right, Ronny.
Tomorrow night
is Beth's parents'
anniversary party.
Forty years.
I really think you can
learn something from it.
I want you to soak it in.
Oh, and, by the way,
we did just move
into the red zone.
Hey, Felix,
the algorithm is solid,
so it's got to be
the hardware, right?
Yeah, looks like it.
Yeah, well, keep at it.
Okay. I got it,
I'm on it.
Do you want to
kiss Felix? Come in.
Come here.
Don't be shy, baby.
You can join us. Yeah.
Good night, guys.
I'm sorry,
I don't mean to make you
feel uncomfortable.
(STAMMERS) I'm not a pervert
or anything, I'm sorry.
That's too bad.
I'm sorry?
I said, that's too bad.
Right.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
(GROANS)
Yo.
RONNY: Hey,
I just wanted to call
and say thanks
for your support today.
I really appreciate it.
(STAMMERS) No problem.
So, what are you doing?
I'm just at home.
Home?
Yes, I'm at home.
Yeah? You want
to get a beer?
You know what? I can't.
Mad Men marathon
with Geneva tonight.
You're right, I really...
I got to shut down
the engine sometimes.
Why you looking in?
No peep Tom.
Yes.
You come in or you go!
I'm going to go.
Go.
No, I have things.
You go.
And you go, too.
Who was that?
It's a traffic cop.
They've shut down
North Avenue.
They're shutting stuff down,
there's too many people.
Hold on,
this guy is a prick.
I'm not even driving!
I'm walking around here,
I'm a citizen!
Mr. Mountain High!
Hold on. Hey.
We make you so happy!
When you leave here,
you will smile like boy
who just got off braces,
big and proud!
Boon-me is back in country,
and looks very forward
to seeing you.
Yeah, look,
I got to go.
What was that?
Nothing, there's a war film
on bef ore Mad Men.
Listen, I'm going to go.
I'll call you.
RONNY: Buddy,
just so you know,
if you ever want to talk
about anything, just like...
There's nothing
we can't talk about.
Yeah, we can always talk.
I thought tonight could
be good, 'cause maybe
we could get a drink.
NICK: All right,
I got to run.
Boon-me is waiting.
I just... I wanted to
call and let you know
that I've been thinking
about what you were saying
with the curtain
and all that stuff.
And I just want to
make sure that I'm being
fair to you during this,
and that I do realize that
there's probably two sides
to every story.
Oh, Jesus Christ!
Ronny, you followed him
to the massage parlor?
(STAMMERS) Well, no,
I just wanted to call
and let you know
that I'm sure
that not everything that
you're saying is bullshit.
And that if there is
complicated things
that are going on,
I really hope you guys
work on it.
And just so you know,
I really don't want
to be in this, Geneva.
I know.
It's your shot,
come on!
Wait, who was that?
Where are you?
I'm at home.
Except it's your shot,
Geneva,
and you don't own
a fucking pool table!
Ronny, I got to go.
What happened to, "I'm not
gonna see this guy anymore
until after I talk to Nick"?
Good night, Ronny.
Yeah, good night, princess.
Just make sure you're ready
to talk to your husband
when you go home tonight,
honey.
Because I'm definitely
going to talk to him!
Okay, just take a breath.
(SIGHS)
Besides, I have something
you might want to hear
before you go and do that.
What is it?
I ordered you some coffee.
I don't need your
goddamn coffee, Geneva,
I don't have anything
to talk to you about.
I'm gonna go
see Nick tonight,
and I'm going to tell him
that his wife is sick
and twisted,
and that she's a liar.
And I'm going to tell him
that he's married to
goddamn Helen Keller.
Helen Keller?
Yeah.
The girl with
all the personalities.
Sybil.
Yeah, Sybil.
Who are you today, Blanche?
How deep do the waters run?
You're a five-year-old
on a playground, Ronald.
It's not like I want
to go and see Zip.
But when my husband
calls me to explain he has
another late meeting,
it kind of just flies
out the window.
"Zip"? That's
the guy's name, Zip?
The point is, Ronny,
I don't want any of this.
I love my husband.
You got a real funny
way of showing that.
Stay out of my life.
You're not a therapist.
In fact, you need one,
desperately.
Look in the mirror.
You're 40 years old,
you've never been married.
Go fix yourself and
then you can call me.
I don't need to call you,
I don't need
to say anything
to you anymore.
All I need to do is get out
of here and go tell Nick
that his wife is cheating.
And I guess, because
you weren't able to do
the things
that you really said
you needed to do
that that's just the way
it's going to have to go
down, honey.
You know what?
I see it going down
just a little bit differently.
Really?
Yeah.
Because I'm going
to deny it.
And then I'm going to say
you made a pass at me.
I made a pass at you?
Yep.
And considering
our little secret,
I'm pretty sure
he'll believe me.
Geneva, okay...
We both decided
not to say anything
because you liked him,
and we didn't want
to ruin something good
over a drunken
college night
that happened
three months before you
two ever started dating.
But, Ronny,
he doesn't know that.
It didn't mean
anything, Geneva.
Yeah? Well, it means
something now, doesn't it?
See, you need to understand
how this is going
to play out, Ronny.
I'm going tell him
how we slept together
all those years ago,
and then I'm going to say
that you started
making passes at me.
And that they never stopped.
You do that.
You sell him that
I've been hitting on you
for 20 years straight.
(SOBBING)
I should've told you, Nick,
I should've told you sooner.
But Ronny insisted that
we not say anything.
But as the years went on,
it got harder and harder
and I just lied to myself
and said it didn't matter.
(SNIFFLING)
But I'm telling you this now
because Ronny has gone crazy!
He's been throwing me up
against restaurant walls
right when you're right
around the corner.
It's like he wants you to see,
he wants to get caught
because he feels so guilty.
But I don't feel safe
anymore, Nick!
Okay.
And this had to come out.
Then what are you
going to do, Ronny?
Mr. Moral Guy.
Are you going to
look your best friend in
the eyes, and lie to him
and say,
"No, that never happened.
I never slept with her"?
I don't think so.
Stay out of my marriage.
Now if you'll excuse me.
Good night, Sybil.
I don't even know
if you're there, God.
I haven't really tried
to ring you up
ever since I asked
for those parlays
when things were tough.
And I know you didn't
help me with those
for my own good
because I had stuff
I had to learn, but...
I don't want to learn
any lessons on this one.
I really don't want to
lose my best friend.
I know I'm supposed
to give you things,
(SOBBING) but I'm scared
to give you this.
If you are listening,
and if you want to help us
with the whole Chrysler thing,
that would be
really great, too.
If that could go our way,
that would be really great.
If you're listening,
that's it.
(PHONE RINGING)
Hello.
MAN: Can I speak
to Beth Dalton?
She's not here right now.
May I take a message?
Thanks, but no.
(PHONE CLICKS)
Hello?
(SPEED DIALING)
MAN: Good morning.
You've reached
the Kearny Group.
How may I help you?
The Nikon D5000.
Ten-million
effective pixels,
2.7 pixel density.
Does it work
from far away?
Definitely. Are you
gonna be shooting birds?
Yes.
What kind?
Unfaithful ones.
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Hello?
Hey, it's me. I need to
see you, it's important.
Who is this?
Susan Warner.
The consultant for Dodge.
Oh, yes, of course, Susan.
I'm sorry, I thought we were
in "it's me" territory
in our relationship.
No, we are,
we absolutely are.
What's up?
Get your ass
to Marino Chrysler
right now.
I don't want to do this
over the phone.
SUSAN: There are
powers at work here.
But this is it,
this is the end game.
This is what it's about.
It's about your engine
in that car.
The sound of your
engine in that car,
the vibration of your
engine in this car.
Susan, I get it.
Just tell me
what exactly the hiccup is.
Thomas loved your idea,
but he doesn't want
to only depend on
B & V to execute it.
So he threw the bid
to United Design.
That's bullshit!
He can't throw our bid
to United Design!
RONNY:
That's our idea!
SUSAN: Exactly.
They're worried about Nick.
"Can he finish?
Can he handle this?"
That's nuts. That's crazy,
'cause Nick Brannen will
bring the thing home.
He's next-level genius.
Yeah! You preaching
to the choir, here.
That's why
I'm telling you this.
I'm on your side.
I'm your Deep Throat.
Well, I appreciate it.
Did you ever
see that movie?
All the President's Men?
No, Deep Throat.
Uh-uh.
Oh.
It's pretty amazing.
Okay, Susan, I'm sorry,
but can you just tell me,
when is United Design
supposed to present?
In three days.
Unbelievable.
RONNY: I didn't
make the deadline,
but we have to hit it.
Listen, Felix,
just get Nick for me?
Nick is sleeping
in the '68 Charger.
Do you want me
to wake him?
No, just tell him
when he wakes up.
Okay.
I got that information
that you wanted right here.
The Kearny Group
is a Las Vegas-based
private equity group
that brings well-known
restaurants to Vegas.
Uh-huh.
They did Rao's,
II Mulino, and Le Cirque.
All right, thanks,
Felix. I got to run.
(CAR ENGINE STARTING)
(COUNTRY ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
(GENEVA CHUCKLES)
(DOG BARKING)
(GENEVA LAUGHING)
(GENEVA SHRIEKS)
(SULTRY MUSIC PLAYING
IN THE ROOM)
(GENEVA WHOOPS)
(GRUNTS)
(CLICKING)
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
Hello.
Hey, Ronny,
where are you?
I'm doing all different
kinds of things now,
with all the nice people,
thank you.
(STAMMERS)
All right, listen,
I just got your message.
Three days? I don't
think I can do it.
I thought we were
on the 10-yard line,
but I think the refs
might be reviewing the call.
You're going to have to
make the plays now, Nick.
Why do you sound like
you're on medication?
You're great at what you do.
You're a very sweet man. Okay.
(GENEVA CHUCKLING)
(ZIP KISSES)
BOY 1: All right, man,
you're up. Let's do it!
BOY 2: All right,
you better stick it, dude!
(BOY 2 EXCLAIMS)
Watch this, man!
(BOYS CHATTERING)
MAN: There they are.
Happy anniversary, guys.
WOMAN: Happy anniversary!
Hey! There they are!
Hiya, Dad!
Hi, baby!
It's so great
to see you.
How was the trip, okay?
Wonderful, terrific.
Hey, Mom!
You look ravishing!
Where's Ronny?
Um...
He'll be here in a minute.
Just a little tied up at work.
Okay, good.
(SKATEBOARD CLATTERING)
ZIP: Hey, what did I say?
Come on, get out of here.
Nah, I'm not gonna
be nice anymore.
ZIP: You're bringing down
my property value.
You need to go.
I told you twice already.
I don't want to see you
in front of my place.
BOY: Whatever, man.
Get out of here.
Hi, Sepia,
on Jefferson.
(GRUNTING)
Did you get a good show?
Where are you going?
You're not
going anywhere!
You broke into
the wrong house, boy.
You came to party?
You're going to get
something now!
Get away from me,
you son of a bitch!
You want to party?
Come on, I got all
the party you want, baby!
I just took an OxyContin
20 minutes ago.
I won't feel a thing.
Come on.
Let's get jacked up!
Come on!
Yeah, let's get
jacked up, daddy!
Do you know how much
that guitar cost?
(GRUNTS)
(GROANS) My fish!
You son of a bitch!
You think you're safe
in there? Huh?
We'll see how safe
you are in there, boy!
Oh, yeah!
Yeah, that's right!
You hear me?
I'm going to chew my way
right up your ass, boy!
Yeah! You got
nowhere to go!
(YELLING)
Oh, yeah!
(YELLS) Hey!
I'm going to burn
that face!
What are you doing?
I'm going to burn
your face, boy!
What, are you crazy? Stop!
Give me that
stupid-looking face!
What's wrong?
I thought you were on Oxy?
I'm going to burn it!
You better run,
you son of a bitch!
(GRUNTING)
(GROANING)
Where are you at?
Where are you at, crazy?
Come on, show me!
Oh, you better run, punk!
You better goddamn
run tonight!
I know where
you live, man!
I want that to register.
Put that in
your tattooed mind!
I know where you live!
(DOG BARKING)
Because I'm going
to come back here
and I will burn
that face, daddy!
Oh, I can't wait
for my chance.
I can't wait till I get you,
just lined up perfect
and I get to burn
that little face!
Because I'm a problem!
Now you deal with that!
(PANTING)
(EXHALES DEEPLY)
Whoa!
Crazy's here, baby!
This is a collector's item!
What do you want to do?
You're going to burn my face?
You're going to burn
my face? Yeah?
No! No!
Who are you?
Oh, you're not
going to tell me?
Who are you?
I'm her husband's
best friend!
You son of a bitch!
Oh, shit.
Yeah.
All right, man.
Why didn't you
just say that?
That's right,
you son of a bitch,
I'm her husband's
best friend!
Hold on a second,
calm down. Okay, okay.
You're going to use
a little bat on me?
You think that bat's
going to help you with me?
You could've just said...
No, no, no!
(GROANING)
You're being childish.
Just stop.
Turn over!
Just turn over.
Hey! Hey! Stop.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
Stop, stop.
Do it!
Do it, you scumbag.
Hit me in the head!
You better end this today,
because I'm going
to come back for you.
You understand me?
There's no coming back.
No, I'm going to end
this right now!
My friend Nick
is 10 times the man
you'll ever be.
You're not anything.
You're garbage.
Come on, I'm not...
I didn't even...
That's... (SIGHING)
It takes two,
and you know that!
Yeah, it takes two.
Not three, prick.
(SNIFFLING)
What, are you sniveling?
What?
Are you crying?
No.
No, it's the Oxy,
and it's making me...
Come here! Get up!
Come here!
Get up.
You get up right now.
You get out of here!
Get out of here!
I'm not playing with you!
I'm not playing.
(SNIFFLING)
(SOBS SOFTLY)
I can just take the sweater.
Okay.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Ronny, jeez!
You look like hell!
The sweater's good,
though, right?
Hey! Hi.
Hey, I know I'm late.
I'm hoping I'm still
fashionable. (LAUGHS)
What happened to your face?
Just a bar fight.
Some bikers...
Bar fight, Ronny?
Really?
Yeah.
I was at the Zip Bar
and Grill, actually.
Real dirtbag joint.
Do not go there.
Take it off the GPS.
Let's do this.
Where's the fam?
You know what?
I got to talk to you
for a second. Come here.
Should I see the family?
Okay.
NICK: (WHISPERS)
What is all this?
Come over here. Look,
obviously, something's
going on with you.
And I want you to know
that if you need me,
for anything at all...
Screw the project,
screw the deadline.
I'm there for you,
all right?
Ronny...
Whoa!
You look like shit.
Thank you.
Anyway, thank you.
I pressed Saul
and he totally caved,
admitted he was cheating.
Now we're going
to work on it,
for the kids.
It might be futile,
but you got to
at least try, right?
And all those times
he was saying,
"I'm going bowling."
Yeah, he wasn't bowling.
He wasn't even
bowling at all.
Ronny? What the...
Ron?
(LAUGHING)
(GRUNTS)
Get a good feel, buddy?
Ronny!
You remember
my cousin James,
and his boyfriend Juan?
Let me finish.
Because families
like to touch and hang out,
and that's what we're doing.
I'm just roughing it up
with my guy!
Come on, I had him!
I had him, Juan!
Nice to meet you, buddy!
My guy, good to see you,
babe!
And my parents.
Ronald.
Yeah, Burt and Sue.
It's impressive, 40 years,
it's quite an accomplishment.
Is the flame still
burning after 40?
Still there.
Of course it is,
of course it is.
With you, there's
no question. My man.
Let's go celebrate.
Let's do this.
I'm just playing the fun part,
doing the things I do.
Great to see you!
Breath against breath,
breathe me life.
Thousand and thousand kisses,
give me, I beg you.
Love wants everything
without condition.
Love has no law.
Mom and Dad,
your love has no law.
(PEOPLE EXCLAIMING)
So beautiful.
I'd like to make the toast.
Forty years.
That is a long time
to be with someone.
Forty years, wow!
It's impressive.
I personally don't know
a lot about marriage,
but I would imagine
it can't be easy,
all those 40 years
being with someone.
Because people
are not perfect.
People make
mistakes in life.
But I would assume
what would get you through
those 40 years would be...
...honesty.
Honesty and honesty alone.
And love.
But even more than that,
Burt, is the honesty.
SUE: Don't forget
about patience.
Oh, no one's going to
forget about patience, Sue.
You can relax,
patience is on the table.
(CHUCKLES)
What I'm talking about,
though, is honesty here.
Talking about two people
who have probably
had an eye wander
every now and then.
Everyone knows Burt was
in the garment business.
If you don't think
you meet a lot of girls
in that business,
then you don't get out
of the house much.
A lot of girls.
A lot.
Good-looking guy,
well-spoken.
It's "pinch me,
I'm dreaming time,"
am I right, ladies?
And look at Sue.
Gorgeous lady,
easy to be around.
Always into the aerobics.
Kept it tight,
in a great way.
And Burt did well,
they have a pool.
Pool guy come over.
Lot of guys would
come over to the house.
Young guys, too.
Now let's say
something did happen.
We don't know that
it did, maybe it didn't.
But it's not up to us to know,
it's up to them to know.
I bet they were honest
with each other.
I bet she came to him
and said, "Hey, Burt,
"you know you're
my number one.
"But maybe Mama
got thirsty last night."
(GASPS)
What I'm going to focus on,
though, here is the ingredient
that I think really makes
the whole stew stick together,
and that is honesty.
And similar interests!
Who are you?
I'm Cousin Betty.
First?
Second.
Okay, Cousin Betty,
this is not a group toast
nor is it an open forum.
I'm the one who's
standing up here.
I'm the one with the glass,
I'm the one that is talking.
Now, Burt and Sue chime in
and that's fine because
it's their night, you know,
40 years and all of that.
But not you.
Nobody gave you
a speaking part,
nobody cares.
You're a second cousin,
which isn't even
a real relative
because someone could have
sex with a second cousin
and the kid could
still be normal.
Honesty.
You cannot run from it.
And believe me,
it'll find you.
The truth will
always find you.
Burt and Sue.
Forty years, being honest.
ALL: Burt and Sue.
Congratulations.
(WHISPERS) Can I speak
to you in the kitchen?
I was just going
to finish my...
Please?
Sure.
Okay.
I need to know
what's going on.
Nothing.
I'm just toasting,
and I'm passionate
about honesty.
I'm not talking about
the inappropriate toast
that you just gave at
my parents' anniversary,
or the bar fight,
or the allergies that
you caught from street plants
while chasing fat kids.
I'm talking about
what's going on in your head
that's causing these things.
It's just some stuff
that I have to fix.
That's it, honey.
And I can't bring
you in on it
because that would
directly affect
my ability to do that.
To do what?
To fix it!
Fix it, fix it!
I have to fix it
on my own, honey.
Okay, Ronny,
you're not fixing anything
and you're breaking
more stuff.
And it's enough!
You just gave a whole
speech about honesty,
it's time for you
to be honest with me!
Is it?
Yeah.
Is it honest time
now, between us?
Then why don't
you start, Beth?
Why don't you tell me
about the Kearny Group?
(NERVOUS CHUCKLING EXHALE)
How do you know
about the Kearny Group?
Are you going
to Las Vegas?
Are you planning
on leaving me?
God, Ronny, no! No!
They asked me
to open up a restaurant in
City Center, and I said no.
Why?
Because that would mean
I'd have to go live
in Las Vegas for
a couple of years.
And...
And what, Beth?
And I don't trust you
in Las Vegas.
Okay.
Ronny...
Look at you.
Your sponsor called me.
You haven't been going
to your meetings,
you're walking around
with large amounts of cash,
and it just really feels
like two years ago.
You know, I...
I can't get into this
with you right now.
If you don't let me in,
how do I know what to do?
How can I help you?
I think it's best if I go.
I don't want you to go.
I'm going to go sleep
at the office tonight.
You want to do this?
(CLEARS THROAT)
What are you doing?
(WHISPERING)
Watching you sleep.
It's creepy, right?
Felix, go play with
the hot tub and the ladies
on the line, honestly.
I'm just getting up,
it's too much.
You're too much.
Please, give me a minute,
I don't know where I'm at.
Oh, God.
Hey, man.
What's going on?
Come on in the house.
What, are you going to
shoot me right here
on your porch in
broad daylight?
Are you out of your mind?
No, not if you're
in the house.
I've googled this.
Do you want to know
how it works? Yeah?
You come inside
and I defend myself.
Now, I'm not going to
pump six bullets into you.
No, that would make me
look crazy and out of control.
No, I'm going to pump
three into you like
a calm gun-owner would.
Zip, I came here
with the intent,
and only the intent,
of getting my camera back.
(STUTTERS) Oh, yeah.
Your camera?
Come on inside.
If you just
want your camera,
it's right here.
Listen to me.
I can really appreciate
the fact that things got
completely nuts
the other night.
And I can also appreciate
that a lot of your property...
I appreciate the fact
that a lot of your property
got damaged as well.
(VOICE BREAKING)
You killed my fish.
You killed my fish, man.
I know.
Why would you do that?
Maybe you should be
compensated for that.
You should be
I can't put a price on that,
because that's a friend.
Although you can't pet it,
but what would the fish do?
The fish doesn't
want this, man.
I think what the fish
is saying is maybe I should
get my camera back.
And maybe, just maybe,
and I'm just hoping
against hope here,
maybe we can put
this whole thing behind us.
$10,000.
$500.
$5,000.
I have a thousand.
I'll give you the thousand.
And an apology.
Zip, if I apologize to you
when you have a gun pointed
at my throat,
then I don't think
it really counts.
(CHUCKLES)
That's a good point.
I'm sorry for what happened.
I need to feel it.
I just need it to really
come from right there.
Look, man,
I'm sorry, all right?
I'm sorry.
I'm really sorry.
I'm really, really sorry
that we're standing
here in this situation.
I'm sorry.
Okay.
(SIGHING)
...seven, eight, nine, 10.
And the $400 I owe for
the old person's home.
Perfect.
You did this to me.
You know that.
I don't mess with firearms.
I don't do that.
I don't do that. Look,
I'm a sensitive guy.
You know what
I'm saying to you?
Okay.
Thank you.
Drive safe.
(KNOCKS ON DOOR)
Who the hell are you?
You got no choice now.
You got to go right up to him
and just say it to him.
It's not that complicated
of a thing to do. It's easy.
You got the pictures,
she can't bullshit you,
and that's the end of it.
Come here.
Get in here,
I love you.
Stop it, you will find
somebody else.
You're a great guy,
and I love you.
Just keep walking.
Ronny.
Hey.
We were just about
to call you, actually.
We were hoping to be
a little better prepared,
but I guess
we can start?
Ronny, why don't you
come join us?
Who are you?
My name is Dr. Rosenstone.
Your family and friends
are here because
they love you, Ronald.
And they can't stand
to see you destroy
yourself anymore.
What is this,
an intervention?
(CRYING) Yes!
ROSENSTONE: We don't see
the need for labels.
This is just
a bunch of friends
talking to one friend
and letting them
know they love them.
An intervention.
Your sister and her husband
would like to start.
I tormented you, I know.
Diane, please don't do this.
I dressed you up
like a little girl,
but I'm here
to support you.
DIANE: Ronny, I am!
Okay, okay.
It's not what you think.
(WHISPERING) I don't know
how the hell you found out,
but I'll kill you
if you ever do
that to me again.
Okay.
BETH: Why don't we all
come in and sit down?
Come on.
Let Ronny sit down.
DIANE:
We got a big blue chair
waiting for Ronny.
Come on, sweetheart,
sit down. It'll be okay.
ROSENSTONE:
Well, it's no coincidence
that we find ourselves here
in a gentle circle of support.
Hey.
Oh, shit, am I late?
I'm sorry. I know
it's probably really bad form
to be late to an intervention.
Hi, I'm Beth.
Hi, Beth.
What's going on?
Hey, big guy.
Who the hell invited him?
NICK: You know what?
I invited him.
You did?
You invited him?
Yeah. You know what?
I followed you to
his place earlier today.
I saw you pay him.
And after you left,
I went up and talked to him.
(MESSAGE TONE BEEPS)
It says right here,
"If possible, it's best to
have all enablers present,
"even bookies."
So I agreed to pay your debt
if he agreed to come here
tonight, and he did.
Thanks, man.
I appreciate this.
It was really nice
of you. No problem.
You got to be kidding me.
He's not my bookie, Nick.
ZIP: Oh, come on, Ronny.
Admit it, man.
You bet on everything.
How dare you show up here!
You have no right being here!
He's a scumbag,
an enabler, a mistake!
NICK: Stop it!
I asked him to come here!
Come on, don't kill
the messenger.
I'm just here to help.
I'm helping.
ZIP: Okay?
That's what I'm doing.
Look, he bets on
the Bulls, and the Sox,
the Cubs.
He bet on the Hawaii game.
Only degenerates bet
on the Hawaii game.
I don't want that
for you, man.
I should have done
this a long time ago.
I think you need to
take a look at this.
(CAMERA BUTTON CLICKS)
What is...
You got to look,
there's more pictures.
You got to flip through
that one, get to
the other pictures.
I did.
I'm flipping
right now.
I keep flipping, and it keeps
going back to the same pic
because there's
only one picture
in the catalogue.
You can't take a picture
of something that
didn't happen, Ronald.
Son of a bitch.
DIANE: (GASPS) Ronny!
Not again.
SAUL: Ronny, calm down!
NICK: Stop it!
You're going to kill him!
You're going to kill
your bookie!
He's not
my damn bookie!
There's something
wrong with you!
You son of a bitch!
What is wrong with you?
You're completely
out of control!
You're crazy!
You're completely
out of your mind!
Don't get me wrong,
I'd like to party with you
and get high with you,
but you're insane!
I think we're missing
the point of this gathering.
It's about talking
and sharing our concerns.
This is ridiculous.
Then let me go, okay?
Because I have
something to say.
Take a seat.
Please, everybody, sit.
Beth, please.
Just sit down.
Look, here's the thing...
Please, just let me...
Please, okay?
All right.
Ah, man, that was...
All right, I got
something to say.
This is important
to me, so...
(CLEARS THROAT)
Okay, Nick...
All right,
please.
Please?
I didn't have many friends
when I got to Ball State.
I was shy and...
You already know this.
But, Ronny,
what you don't know is
when you moved
in across the hall,
in second semester,
I made it a goal of mine
to become friends with you.
I mean, you were funny
and charming,
and everybody liked him,
everybody.
Okay, Nick, enough.
You got to let me
talk here for a second.
I want you
to listen to me.
Nick, you're
my best friend.
You always make me
do better.
You always make sure
I don't screw up.
And you make it
that I never forget what
really matters in life.
When I had my relapse
two years ago,
it wasn't all the money
and stuff that I lost
that made me feel bad.
It was the fact that
I let you down.
ROSENSTONE:
This is good.
This is catharsis.
I know.
You know
I never had a brother
growing up, right?
And my dad wasn't
around very much.
And all my friends
growing up were,
really, criminals.
So when I met you
in school, I was...
Let's just say
that I looked up to you
as well, in college.
And I really have looked up
to you ever since.
So, there's something
that you should know.
There's something that
I already should have
told you, Nick.
What is it?
Geneva's been
running on you
with the guy
that you thought
was my bookie.
Jesus Christ, Ronny!
You thought that you saw
an exchange, right?
That it was a gambling
exchange,
but it wasn't
a gambling exchange.
Really, I was just going
to get my camera,
because there were
pictures and stuff on it.
The truth is,
I'm not gambling.
I haven't been doing
any gambling at all.
What's been going on
with me is
I've really been trying
to figure out what's
the best way to tell you
and how to handle
this thing.
Is this true?
No! It's not true.
He's lying!
He's compulsive,
he's a gambler.
He'll say anything,
he's desperate!
Go ahead, Geneva,
tell him the truth.
Everyone is sitting here,
listening.
Okay, fine, fine!
Uh...
The thing is, that...
(GENEVA SIGHS)
Okay, fine.
(GENEVA STAMMERS)
What did you expect?
You were getting
happy endings in Pilsen.
Jeez!
(GASPS)
No! No, Nick, listen.
You left me alone.
I wanted to be
with you, but...
Can we not get
into this right now?
No, but that's the problem!
You never want to talk
about anything, ever!
I know that
it's been tough with us
for a while now,
and I take my part
in that.
But isn't there
something about us
you still believe in?
(SIGHS)
How long did you know?
I've known for
a few days, a week.
For way too long.
I don't know what to say.
I don't even know what
I'm feeling right now.
Honestly, I don't know!
I do know this,
you should have
told me sooner, Ronny.
Before right now.
Before standing here
in front of your friends
and your family, and Doctor...
(PANTING) Rose...
I know it starts with "Rose."
Rosenstone.
...stone.
Buddy, I know.
I'm really sorry.
I tried to tell you
in the office.
What do you mean trying?
Trying is not telling, Ronny!
Come on. Look,
I can appreciate
how hard this must
have been on you,
I know.
I'm just really glad
that you say that you can
appreciate how hard it was
because you don't
even know.
I've been fighting
with these people,
trying to keep everything
straight in my head.
NICK: I get it.
RONNY: But in the nature
of what's going on here,
there's one more small thing
that I just want to bring
closure to now
in the circle
of gentleness.
Ronny, you don't have to.
Yes, I do, Geneva.
Because Nick is
my best friend.
And this is what
best friends do.
They tell the truth
to each other.
Okay. When
we were in college,
and this is way before
you guys ever met,
there was a night
that didn't mean anything.
It was a meaningless night.
It was a booze night.
It was big,
big bar night.
Ronny, get to the point.
The point is, way before
you guys ever met,
before you ever even
knew each other,
I kind of slept
with Geneva.
You what?
This is what friends do,
they tell the truth.
I'm a friend and
I'm telling the truth,
buddy. Here I am.
GENEVA: He wanted
to tell you, Nick.
But I was falling
in love with you.
We didn't want to hurt you.
You asshole!
Hold on, hold on.
I'm telling the truth,
I'm in a circle.
No, you know what?
You're the worst.
Buddy, I'm sorry,
okay? Listen...
Get your hands off me.
Don't touch me!
Let me tell you something.
That's probably
the most honest thing
you've ever said to me.
Nick...
You're sorry.
You're so sorry.
Nick.
(DOOR SLAMS)
I'm sorry, Ronny.
I'm sorry.
I should never have
put you in that position.
Beth, I am so sorry
that I caused tension
between you two.
I'm sorry.
(DOOR CLOSING)
This has been
a marvelous first step.
I'm sorry?
This has been
a revelation for you,
I can tell.
I'm okay, buddy. Thank you.
You've done a lot here today.
(DOOR OPENING)
I didn't gamble.
I walked by the casino
once or twice,
but I didn't gamble.
Are you okay?
It's been a long day.
I didn't know if you
had eaten or not, so,
if you're hungry...
(EXHALES)
I don't know how
to start this.
I got scared.
And I'm sorry,
because I didn't feel safe.
So then, I didn't tell you
about Las Vegas
and the Kearny Group.
And then, here I am,
being someone that
I don't want to be.
I mean, I staged
this whole ridiculous
intervention thing
(CRYING)
and you weren't
even gambling!
And that's great,
by the way.
I'm so happy that
you weren't gambling.
But this is no good.
It's not healthy.
The problem is,
if you don't share
stuff with me,
like the fact that
you were with Geneva,
it keeps me in the dark.
And that belittles us.
I want us to be
more than that.
I understand.
I just didn't feel right
in saying something to you
if I wasn't
saying it to Nick.
And then,
when I found out
about the Vegas deal
and that you didn't trust me
enough to share that with me,
then that really hurt.
But I guess
I've earned that.
And it's up to me
to un-earn that.
I don't ever want to
put you through anything
like this ever again.
Because honestly,
honey, I do love you.
I love you, too.
And...
I understand.
You've got a Chrysler meeting
tomorrow, don't you?
I don't even know
if Nick is going to show up.
You weren't
a terrible friend, Ronny.
I mean,
you sucked at the way
you handled things,
but you cared.
(SIGHS)
(LAUGHS)
Yes.
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
Ronny Valentine,
the other half of the team.
I'll let the gang know,
tell them you're both here.
Thank you.
I appreciate that.
(CLEARS THROAT)
(EXHALING)
How are you doing?
Well, I moved out.
How are you feeling?
(SIGHING)
Shaky
on how everything
went down.
The truth is, I was just
hanging on to something
that wasn't there.
It wasn't fair to her.
I'm sorry, buddy.
I'm sorry you're going
through this, Nick.
Listen, I feel terrible
about the whole situation.
And I've been
sick to my stomach for
the last 24 hours, man.
(SIGHING)
I've been doing
a lot of soul-searching
and thinking about
what friendship really means.
And the thing of it is...
(GROANS)
There it is.
Okay, good. That's good.
Nick, I feel terrible
about this whole thing,
all right?
And if that makes
you feel better,
for me, honestly,
I just want to get
past this thing, okay?
So, if you want
to hit me again...
Ow!
(COUGHING)
Oh, my God.
Is everything all right?
Great. (COUGHS)
We're ready for you.
We'll be just one sec.
We're ready,
we'll come right in.
Well, we'll be in
the presentation area.
RONNY: I know where it is,
I'll be right there.
Good grief.
We're really looking forward
to this opportunity.
(RONNY CONTINUES COUGHING)
You handled this
whole thing like shit.
I'm sorry, Nick.
I really am.
I know I didn't
date a lot,
so when Geneva
and I were serious,
you didn't want
to hurt me,
and it was before
we ever got together.
Now I'm not saying
it was easy,
the spot you were in,
because it wasn't.
But in the future,
no matter
how uncomfortable
things are,
if it affects us,
you got to tell me.
Do you got it?
I promise you, Nick.
I got it.
(GRUNTS)
Okay.
All right, there you go.
I'm good.
(EXHALES)
Excuse me, Mr. Valentine,
given what we just saw
in the waiting room,
I think we need to...
Oh, that?
We're like kids in a car
too long on a road trip.
We're fine,
we're just working.
The moment of truth
has finally arrived.
Now I know that
the journey getting here
has had some turbulence
and some confusion.
But I ask you
for one second,
when folks were
reaching for greatness,
was that not the case?
I remember a group of people
who wanted to head west
with dreams of gold
and opportunity.
The Donner Party.
The Donner Pass.
Things got a little weird
out on the trail, didn't it?
(COYOTE HOWLING)
Some cannibalism,
folks got hungry.
Some feelings hurt,
some families destroyed,
but some people
made it out west.
Not all of them.
And it's not that
they necessarily got rich.
But the point is,
we've headed out west,
and this is our destination.
Nick,
start your engine.
(CAR ENGINE STARTING)
(ENGINE PURRING)
(CAR ENGINE ROARING)
You son of a bitch.
(TURNS OFF ENGINE)
I told you the difference
was Nick Brannen,
and we have Nick Brannen.
(SINGING)
Simply the best
You can feel it.
(SINGING)
Better than all the rest
You were right about
these lunatics, Susan.
Commit to the long-term deal
and cut them a check.
(LAUGHS) And that's why
I love you guys!
That's why I love you!
That's why my lady wood
is still strong!
See, I get it.
They don't get it.
They don't get it,
but I do.
See,
all that fighting and shit,
that's just passion!
When you work that close,
you just want to choke
the hell out of
somebody, right?
Yeah.
See, I understand that.
I relate. But, listen.
That motor...
That motor in that car...
I mean, when
it started vibrating...
I'm sorry?
If I was sitting on
the hood of that car...
Okay.
...and the way it was
just vibrating...
I understand,
and I got to be really
honest with you.
When I first met you,
your phraseology
with "lady wood,"
I didn't know
whether you were
coming or going.
But I've really
grown to love you.
(SUSAN LAUGHING)
(CROWD CHEERING)
Yes! Yes!
Come on!
Damn it!
(GROANS)
(CROWD BOOING)
He can do this,
he just has to stay calm.
Nick Brannen, that was
your second shot.
But if you score
on your third
and final attempt,
you can still win
a trip for two
to the NHL All-Star
Game in Carolina.
Are you ready?
Yeah, I'm ready.
Okay, good luck.
Dude, seats are taken.
It's between periods.
I've got food here!
What are you,
a hall monitor?
I'm not touching
your food!
I know the guy!
Nick!
Great moments are born
from great opportunities.
That's what you have
here tonight, Nick.
That's what you've
earned here tonight!
One shot.
You take it 10 times,
you might miss nine.
But not this shot, Nick.
Not tonight.
(EXHALES NERVOUSLY)
Come on, big guy.
Come on, baby.
(BUZZER SOUNDING)
Yes!
Whoo-hoo!
Congratulations
to Nick Brannen
who's won a trip for two
to the NHL All-Star Game
in Carolina.
Yes, you did!
Yeah!
They can never
take it away from you!
(POP SONG PLAYING)
Ronny!
Yes, buddy!
Yeah, Ronny!
I knew you'd do it!
I told you I would do it!
(CHEERING)
(INDISTINCT)
(ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)